Guide to the Amado M. Padilla Papers M0497
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Amado M. Padilla papers
1969-1990
M0497
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
103.0 Linear feet: 204 boxes
Amado Padilla is a professor of psychology who studies Hispanic American bilingualism and mental health. The collection contains correspondence, personal and professional papers, and material from Padilla's work with the Spanish Speaking Mental Health Research Center, National Center for Bilingual Research (including an extensive meta-analysis project), and a small amount of correspondence from the Center for Language Education and Research.
Padilla, Amado M.
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged in four series: Series 1. Correspondence and Personal Papers; Series 2. Spanish-Speaking Mental Health Research Center (SSMHRC); Series 3. National Center for Bilingual Education and Research (NCBR); Series 4. Center for Language Education and Research (CLEAR).
Scope and Contents
The Amado M. Padilla papers support research on such topics as language studies and education, acculturation and ethnicity, and psychosocial stress and well-being with regard to Hispanics in the United States. The Collection spans the years 1969 to 1987, with the bulk of the papers dating from 1976 to 1987. The majority of the collection consists of correspondence (personal and professional), organizational records, and subject files. Letters, notes, agendas, minutes, reports, press releases, publicity documents, financial records, personnel records, articles, monographs, and more are housed in the collection.
The collection is divided into four (3?) series: Correspondence and Personal Papers (including correspondence for The Hispanic Journal of Behavioral Sciences), Spanish-Speaking Mental Health Research Center (SSMHRC), National Center for Bilingual Education and Research (NCBR), and Center for Language, Education, and Research (CLEAR).
Biographical/Historical note
Amado M. Padilla was born in Albuquerque, New Mexico on October 19, 1942. After graduating in 1960 from St. Mary High School, where he was active in sports and earned average grades, Padilla entered New Mexico Highlands University. There he became a serious student and aspired toward an academic career; he was also active in Psi Chi, the national honorary society in psychology. He received a B.A. in Psychology and Sociology in 1964. He began his graduate work at Oklahoma State University, received his M.S. in Experimental Psychology in 1966, and went to The University of New Mexico, where he received his Ph.D. in Experimental Psychology in 1969.
Padilla’s first academic appointment was at the State University of New York, College at Potsdam, where he was the Assistant Professor of Psychology from 1969-1971. He relocated to The University of California, Santa Barbara in 1971, serving as Assistant Professor of Psychology until 1974. In 1974 Padilla accepted an appointment with tenure at the University of California, Los Angeles, where he taught from 1974-1988. Following his term as Visiting Professor at the School of Education at Stanford University in 1986-1987, Padilla was invited to permanently join the Stanford faculty. He came to Stanford in 1988, and presently holds the appointment of Professor of education at the School of Education, where he is involved in the Language, Literacy, and Culture as well as Psychological Studies Programs.
Throughout his career, Padilla has distinguished himself as a premier researcher, with an emphasis on Mexican American bilingualism and Hispanic mental health issues. His research, scholarship, and teaching in these heretofore relatively unexplored areas has placed him at the forefront of the field of Hispanic psychology and mental health, shedding light on critical issues affecting the well-being of Hispanics, and pointing the way for other researchers to undertake study of them. The marked increase over the past fifteen years in the quantity and quality of research on Hispanics psychology and mental health, is largely a consequence of Padilla’s work in identifying the important research areas, and conducting much of the work himself and with his colleagues and students.
Three major and one minor strand characterize Padilla’s research: language studies and education, acculturation and ethnicity, psychosocial stress and well-being, and the history of psychology. Emphasizing Hispanics in the United States on these topics, Padilla has employed Hispanics as respondents in almost all his studies. Padilla’s approach is multidisciplinary: he collaborates extensively with colleagues in anthropology, applied linguistics, education, history, and sociology in his investigations and publications. As noted earlier, he has led other Hispanic researchers (and researchers interested in Hispanic issues), by always having the dual objective in his work of codifying knowledge while also pointing to research gaps in need of study.
Padilla has held several major administrative positions in conjunction with his academic appointments. In 1973-1974, he served as Director of the Institute for Applied Behavioral Science at The University of California, Santa Barbara; from 1976-1989 he was the Director and Principal Investigator of the Spanish Speaking Mental Health Research Center (SSMHRC) at the University of California, Los Angeles; during 1982-85 he directed the National Center for Bilingual Research (NCBR) in Los Alamitos, California; and in 1985-1988 he acted as Director and Principal Investigator of the Center For Language, Education, and Research (CLEAR) at the University of California, Los Angeles. In addition to directing these research centers, in 1978 Padilla founded The Hispanic Journal of Behavioral Science. During this time, he also established the first Hispanic Health and Mental Health Literature Data Base, a computerized database providing researches with published bibliographies and literature searches.
Padilla’s prolific work in the field of Hispanic psychology and mental health has earned him numerous awards, and his invitations to sit on national panels, review boards, and commissions. In 1977 he was recognized in Who’s Who in Health Care; and in 1977-1978 he was invited to be a Fulbright-Hays Senior Lecturer to the Pontifica Universidad Catolica del Peru in Lima, Peru, where he taught statistics and environmental design and established a psychological laboratory. He was invited to serve from 1978-1981 as an elected member-at-large of the American Association for the Advancement of Science’s Psychology Section J; from 1978-1979 as a member of the National Research Council/National Science Foundation Postdoctoral Fellowship Evaluation Panel (Behavioral and Social Sciences); and from 1979-1981 as a member on the Assembly of Behavioral and Social Sciences’ Panel on Selection and Placement of Students in Programs for the Mentally Retarded. In 1979 he was elected Treasurer of the Interamerican Society of Psychology, a position he held until 1982; from 1982-1984 he served as a member of the American Psychological Association’s Education and Training Board; from 1982-1983 he acted as Chairman of the National Research Council/Ford Foundation Postdoctoral Fellowship for Minorities Program Panel in Psychology; in 1983 and 1984 he served as a member on the American Psychological Association’s Continuing Education and Undergraduate Education Committees; and in 1984-1985 as a member on the National Institute of Drug Abuse’s Epidemiology and Prevention Subcommittee of the Epidemiology, Prevention, and Services Research Review Committee.
Padilla was elected Chairman in 1985 of the American Psychological Association’s Committee on the International Relations in Psychology, a position he held for one year, and in which capacity he traveled to Chile in 1985 as part of the Human Rights Delegation to Chile sponsored by the American Psychological Association and American Committee for Human Rights. Succeeding professional appointments include the California School of Professional Psychology’s Board of Trustees (Member, 1986); the State of California’s Commission for economic Development Task Force for the Seriously Mentally Ill (Member; 1986); the American Educational Research Association’s Outstanding Dissertations Award Committee (Chairman, 1986); the American Psychological Association’s Publication and Communication Board (Member, 1987); and the Carnegie Corporation’s Council on Adolescent Development Task Force on the Education of Early Adolescents (Member, 1987).
Padilla’s great success and recognition in the field of Hispanic psychology and mental health, a field he has essentially established himself, reflect his exceptional academic, professional, and personal abilities. Padilla believes that his achievements are due to the strong belief in the value of education maintained by his parents, Manuel and Esperanza. The oldest of five brothers, Padilla and his brothers hold a total of ten university degrees. His mother also returned to school and at age 55 received her B.A. degree from the University of New Mexico. Padilla’s roots from both sides of the family extend back over two hundred years in New Mexico and he acknowledges that most days he would rather be sitting on the porch of his home in Corrales, New Mexico despite his attraction to Northern California. Padilla is married to Kathryn Lindhom who received her Ph.D at UCLA in Psychology and who is on the faculty at San Jose State.
Related Archival Materials note
Published works by Padilla held by Stanford.
National Center for Bilingual Education and Research (U.S.).; Padilla, Amado M.; Spanish Speaking Mental Health Research Center (U.S.).; Education, Bilingual --United States.; Hispanic Americans; Hispanic Americans--Mental health
- Series 1. Correspondence and Personal Papers
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains Padilla’s correspondence and personal papers for the years 1969-1987, including his correspondence about The Hispanic Journal of Behavioral Sciences (HJBS) from 1978 to 1987. The correspondence and papers are arranged in chronological order, divided into Incoming, Outgoing, Internal, and Other. The correspondence and personal papers are quite comprehensive, covering Padilla’s years at The State University of New York, College at Potsdam; The University of California, Santa Barbara; The University of California, Los Angeles; and to a limited extent, Stanford University (1986-7 academic year, during which time he was a Visiting Professor). While they primarily concern his academic and professional activities outside of the Spanish-Speaking Mental Health Research Center, National Center for Bilingual Education and Research, and Center for Language Education and Research, there is some overlap of correspondence from these orgnaizations.
  - Correspondence
    - Incoming, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Outgoing, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Incoming, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Outoging, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Incoming, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Outgoing, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Internal and Other, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Incoming, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Outgoing, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Internal and Other, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Incoming, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Outgoing, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Internal and Other, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Incoming, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Outgoing, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Internal and Other, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Incoming, 1975 (Box 2, Folders 3-4)
    - Outgoing, 1975 (Box 2, Folders 5-6)
    - Internal, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Other, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Incoming, 1976 (Box 3, Folders 1-4)
    - Outgoing, 1976 (Box 3, Folders 5-6)
    - Internal, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Other, 1976 (Box 3, Folders 8-9)
    - Incoming, 1977 (Box 4, Folders 1-3)
    - Outgoing, 1977 (Box 4, Folders 4-5)
    - Internal, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Other, 1977 (Box 4, Folders 7-9)
    - Incoming, 1978 (Box 4, Folders 10-12)
    - Outgoing, 1978 (Box 5, Folders 1-3)
    - Internal, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Other, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Incoming, Hispanic Journal of Behavioral Sciences (HJBS), 1978 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Outgoing, HJBS, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Internal, HJBS, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Incoming, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Outgoing, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 10, Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Internal, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Other, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Incoming, HJBS, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Outgoing, HJBS, 1979 (Box 6, Folders 5-6)
    - Internal, HJBS, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Incoming, 1980 (Box 6, Folders 8-9)
    - Outgoing, 1980 (Box 6, Folders 10-11)
    - Internal, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Other, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Incoming, HJBS, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Outgoing, HJBS, 1980 (Box 7, Folders 4-6)
    - Internal, HJBS, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Other, HJBS, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Incoming, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Outgoing, 1981 (Box 7, Folders 10-12)
    - Internal, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Other, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Incoming, HJBS, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Outgoing, HJBS, 1981 (Box 8, Folders 2-4)
    - Incoming, 1982 (Box 8, Folders 5-6)
    - Outgoing, 1982 (Box 8, Folders 7-8)
    - Other, 1982 (Box 8, Folders 9)
    - Incoming, HJBS, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Outgoing, HJBS, 1982 (Box 9, Folders 1-3)
    - Incoming, 1983 (Box 9, Folders 4-5)
    - Outgoing, 1983 (Box 9, Folders 6-8)
    - Internal, 1983 (Box 9, Folders 9)
    - Other, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Incoming, HJBS, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Outgoing, HJBS, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 12, Box 10, Folders 1-2)
    - Incoming, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Outgoing, 1984 (Box 10, Folders 4-6)
    - Internal, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Other, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Incoming, HJBS, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Outgoing, HJBS, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 1, Box 10, Folders 10-11)
    - Incoming, 1985 (Box 11, Folders 2-3)
    - Outgoing, 1985 (Box 11, Folders 4-6)
    - Internal, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Other, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Outgoing, HJBS, 1985 (Box 11, Folders 9-11)
    - Incoming, 1986 (Box 12, Folders 1-2)
    - Outgoing, 1986 (Box 12, Folders 3-5)
    - Internal, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Other, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Outgoing, HJBS, 1986 (Box 12, Folders 8-10)
    - Incoming, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 11, Box 13, Folders 1-2)
    - Outgoing, 1987 (Box 13, Folders 3-4)
    - Internal, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Other, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Outgoing, HJBS, 1987 (Box 13, Folders 7-8)
  - Publications, 1967-1979, 1985-1986
    - Articles on or by Padilla (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Padilla, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Logan, Padilla and Boice, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Padilla and Spanier, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Padilla, Ketterer and Giacalone, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Padilla, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Padilla, 1971 (Box 15, Folders 6-8)
    - Padilla, 1972 (Box 15, Folders 9)
    - Padilla and Maciel, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Padilla, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Maciel, Iriart de Padilla and Padilla, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Garza and Padilla, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Padilla and Ruiz, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Padilla and Maciel, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Padilla and Aranda, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Rice, Ruiz and Padilla, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Brand, Ruiz and Padilla, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Maciel and Padilla, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Padilla, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 2, Folder 4)
    - Carlos and Padilla, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Padilla and Ruiz, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Padilla and Liebman, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Padilla and Garza, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Padilla, Ruiz and Alvarez, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Padilla and Romero, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Padilla, 1976 (Box 16, Folders 10-11)
    - Padilla and Lindholm, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 12, Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Padilla, Wagner-Gough, Amero-Plotkin and Amodeo, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Ruiz and Padilla, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Ruiz and Padilla, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Padilla, 1977 (Box 17, Folders 5-6, Folder 11)
    - Padilla, Carlos and Keefe, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Padilla and Padilla, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 8, Folder 10)
    - Lindholm and Padilla, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Lindholm and Padilla, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 12, Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Ruiz, Padilla and Alvarez, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Olmedo and Padilla, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Padilla, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Padilla, Olmedo, Lopez and Perez, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Keefe, Padilla and Carlos, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Padilla, Padilla, Morales, Olmedo and Ramirez, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Bloom and Padilla, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Lindholm, Padilla and Romero, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Padilla, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Publications, 1985-1986 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Appointments, Awards (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Conferences, Meetings (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Series 2. Spanish Speaking Mental Health Research Center (SSMHRC)
  This Series contains Padilla’s correspondence and papers from the Spanish-Speaking Mental Health Research Center, which was established at the University of California, Los Angeles in 1979. Padilla served as Director and Principal Investigator of the SSMHRC from 1979-1989. Documents in this series include correspondence about center work, proposals for center projects, annual progress reports to funding agencies, administrative and personnel records, conference reports, and press releases and publicity. A complete set of center publications is also housed in the series. All documents are arranged chronologically, with correspondence further divided into Incoming, Outgoing, Internal, and Other, with the exception of the set of Center publications, which is arranged alphabetically by author name.
  - Administration
    - Original Proposal, 1 July 1973-30 June 1977., 1973-1977 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Press Releases, 1976 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Publications, 1976 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Reorganization Plan, 1975-10 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - R and D Centers Evaluation (Complete Report), 1977 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Hispanic Health and Mental Health Data Base
    - #1. Drug Abuse/Drug Addiction/Substance Abuse (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - #2. Folk Medicine/Curanderismo/Espiritismo (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - #3. Family Planning/Birth Control/Pregnancy (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - #4. Aggression/Gangs/Delinquency (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - #5. Family Relations/Parental Involvement/Child Rearing Practices (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - #6. Children/Adolescents and Psychotherapy/Psychotherapy Outcome (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - #7. Suicide/Depression (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - #8. Utilization and Community Health Services/Health Delivery Systems (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - #9. Acculturation and Mental Health (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - #10. Stress/Coping Mechanisms (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - #11. Female and Sex Roles/Gender Identity/Role Expectation (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - #12. Female and Self-Concept/Achievement Motivation/Occupational Aspirations (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - #13. Culture--Fair Tests and Personality Assessment/Intelligence Tests/Achievement Testing (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - #14. Alcoholism (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - #15. Discrimination (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - #16. Health (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - SSMHRC Occasional Papers, 1976-1987
    - #1. A. Padilla, Bilingual Schools: Gateways to Integration or Roads to Separation, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - #2. K. Lindholm and A. Padilla, Language Mixing in Bilingual Children, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - #3. F. Castro, Level of Acculturation and Related Consideration in Psychotherapy with Spanish Speaking/Surnamed Clients, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - #4. E. Padilla, A. Padilla, R. Ramirez, A. Morales, and E. Olmedo, Inhalant, Marijuana and Alcohol Abuse among Barrio Children and Adolescents, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - #5. R. Ruiz, J. Casas, A. Padilla, Culturally Relevant Behavioristic Counseling, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - #6. A. Romero, The Mexican American Child: a Sociological Approach to Research, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - #7. S. Keefe, A. Padilla, M. Carlos, Emotional Support Systems in Two Cultures: a Comparison of Mexican Americans and Anglo Americans, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - #8. D. Bloom, A. Padilla, A Peer-Interviewer Model in Conducting Surveys Among Mexican American Youth, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - #9. R. Perez, A. Padilla, A. Ramirez, R. Ramirez, M. Rodriguez, Correlates and Changes over Time in Drug and Alcohol Use within a Barrio Population, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - #10. R. Perez, A. Padilla, A. Ramirez, Expectations toward School Busing in Mexican American Barrio Youth, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - #11. G. Marin, Four Years of Latin American Social Psychology: An Annotated Bibliography for 1976-1979, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - #12. B. Marin, G. Marin, A. Padilla, C. de la Rocha, J. Fay, Health Care Utilization by Low-Income Clients of a Community Clinic: An Archival Study, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - #13. B. Marin, G. Marin, A. Padilla, Attitudes and Practices of Low-Income Hispanic Contraception, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - #14. B. Marin, G. Marin, A. Padilla, C. de la Rocha, Utilization of Traditional and Non-Traditional Sources of Health Care among Hispanics, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - #15. V. Salgado de Snyder and A. Padilla, Interethnic Marriages of Mexican Americans after nearly Two Decades, revised ed., 1985 (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - #16. A. Schmidt, Grandparent-Grandchild Interaction in a Mexican American Group, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - #17. A. Padilla and K. Lindholm, Hispanic Americans: Future Behavioral Science Research Directions, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - #18. K. Lindholm and R. Willey, Child Abuse and Ethnicity: Patterns of Similarities and Differences, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - #19. R. Velasquez, An Atlas of MMPI Group Profiles on Mexican Americans, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - #20. A. Padilla, K. Lindholm, M. Alvarez, and Y. Wagatsuma, Acculturative Stress in Immigrant Studies: Three Papers, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - #21. F. Penalosa, Central Americans in Los Angeles: Background, Language, Education, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - #22. V. Salgado de Snyder, Mexican Immigrant Women: The Relationship of Ethnic Loyalty and Social Support to Acculturative Stress and Depressive Symptomatology, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Other mental health papers
    - Padilla, R. Cervantes, M. Maldonado, and R. Garcia, Coping Responses to Psychosocial Stressors Among Mexican and Central American Immigrants, 1987 (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - R. Cervantes, V. Salgado de Snyder, and A. Padilla, Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder Among Immigrants from Central America and Mexico, 1988 (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - Latino Task Force on Community Mental Health Training, Latino Mental Health, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - R. Alvarez, ed., Delivery of Services for Latino Community Mental Health, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - M. Miranda, ed., Psychotherapy with the Spanish-Speaking: Issues in Research and Service Delivery, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - R. Cervantes and F. Castro, Stress, Coping, and Mexican American Mental Health: A Systematic Review, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - E. Olmedo and S. Lopez, eds., Hispanic Mental Health Professionals, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - A. Padilla, ed., Acculturation. Theory, Models and Some New Findings, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Hispanic Journal of Behavioral Science 4, no. 2, 1982-06 (Box 22, Folder 7)